Guide to the Inge Morath Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers, 1853-2012; Series II; 79.73; (141 boxes) + 7 broadsides, 1 roll; 79.73 linear feet (141 boxes) + 7 broadsides, 1 roll
  - Captions, 1953-2001
    - Magnum New York Set
      - 1954-18 (Box 561)
      - 1954-19 (Box 561)
      - 1954-22 (Box 561)
      - 1954-23 (Box 561)
      - 1954-24 (Box 561)
      - 1955-03 (Box 561)
      - 1955-12 (Box 561)
      - 1955-17 (Box 561)
      - 1955-19 (Box 561)
      - 1955-21 (Box 561)
      - 1955-22 (Box 561)
      - 1955-26 "Extra" (Box 561)
      - 1955-31 (Box 561)
      - 1955-33 (Box 561)
      - 1955-35 (Box 561)
      - 1955-36 (Box 561)
      - 1956-09 (Box 561)
      - 1956-10 (Box 561)
      - 1956-10A (Box 561)
      - 1956-10B (Box 561)
      - 1956-10C (Box 561)
      - 1956-10D (Box 561)
      - 1956-15 (Box 561)
      - 1956-19 (Box 561)
      - 1956-26 (Box 561)
      - 1957-06 (Box 561)
      - 1957-07 (Box 561)
      - 1957-08 (Box 561)
      - 1957-08A (Box 561)
      - 1957-10 (Box 561)
      - 1957-12 (Box 561)
      - 1957-17 (Box 561)
      - "List of contacts in New York", circa 1958 (Box 561)
      - Story index, 1958 (Box 561)
      - [1958-01?] (Box 561)
      - 1958-03 (Box 561)
      - 1958-04 (Box 561)
      - 1958-05 (Box 561)
      - 1958-06 (Box 561)
      - 1958-07 (Box 561)
      - 1958-08 (Box 561)
      - 1958-09 (Box 561)
      - 1958-10 (Box 561)
      - 1958-12 (Box 561)
      - 1958-13 (Box 561)
      - 1958-14 (Box 561)
      - 1958-15 (Box 561)
      - 1958-16 (Box 561)
      - 1958-17 (Box 561)
      - 1958-18 (Box 561)
      - 1958-19 (Box 561)
      - 1958-21 (Box 561)
      - 1958-22 (Box 561)
      - 1958-23 (Box 561)
      - 1958-23, 1959-01, 1958-1959 (Box 562)
      - 1959-02 (Box 562)
      - 1959-03 (Box 562)
      - 1959-04 (Box 562)
      - 1959-05 (Box 562)
      - 1959-06 (Box 562)
      - 1959-07 (Box 562)
      - 1959-08 (Box 562)
      - 1959-09 (Box 562)
      - 1959-12 (Box 562)
      - 1959-16 (Box 562)
      - 1959-19 (Box 562)
      - 1959-21 (Box 562)
      - 1959-24 (Box 562)
      - 1959-25 (Box 562)
      - 1959-29 (Box 562)
      - 1959-31 (Box 562)
      - 1959-32 (Box 562)
      - "Inge Morath: Spain in the 50's," story list, circa 1988 (Box 562)
      - "Inge Morath," brief biographical sketch, 1960 (Box 562)
      - 1960-01 (Box 562)
      - 1960-04 (Box 562)
      - 1960-05 (Box 562)
      - 1960-07 (Box 562)
      - 1960-08 (Box 562)
      - 1960-09 (Box 562)
      - 1960-15 (Box 562)
      - 1960-21 (Box 562)
      - 1960-23 (Box 562)
      - 1961-10 (Box 562)
      - 1961-11 (Box 562)
      - 1961-12 (Box 562)
      - 1961-16 (Box 562)
      - 1961-18 (Box 562)
      - 1961-28 (Box 562)
      - 1961-29 (Box 562)
      - 1961-30 (Box 562)
      - 1961-32 (Box 562)
      - 1961-52 (Box 562)
      - 1963-03 (Box 562)
      - 1963-04 (Box 562)
      - 1963-05 (Box 562)
      - 1963-20 (Box 562)
      - 1963-23 (Box 562)
      - 1963-26 (Box 562)
      - 1963-27 (Box 562)
      - 1963-30 (Box 562)
      - 1963-31 (Box 562)
      - 1964-01 (Box 563)
      - "An Interview with Inge Morath, Mrs. Arthur Miller, a biographical file", 1964 (Box 563)
      - 1964-02 (Box 563)
      - 1964-03 (Box 563)
      - 1964-06 (Box 563)
      - 1964-07 (Box 563)
      - 1964-17 (Box 563)
      - 1965-05 (Box 563)
      - 1965-08 (Box 563)
      - 1965-15 (Box 563)
      - 1965-16 (Box 563)
      - 1965-20 (Box 563)
      - "Spain/War", 1965 (Box 563)
        Photographs by Robert Capa and Morath on the subject of Spain and war with quotes from books by Ernest Hemingway
      - "American Housewife and Family", 1965 (Box 563)
        Text by Elliott Erwitt, photographs by Morath
      - 1966-01 (Box 563)
      - 1966-02 (Box 563)
      - 1966-03 (Box 563)
      - 1966-08 (Box 563)
      - 1966-10 (Box 563)
      - 1966-13 (Box 563)
      - 1966-17 (Box 563)
      - 1967-04 (Box 563)
      - 1967-07 (Box 563)
      - 1967-09 (Box 563)
      - 1967-11 (Box 563)
      - 1968-01 (Box 563)
      - 1968-04 (Box 563)
      - 1968-05 (Box 563)
      - 1968-06 (Box 563)
      - 1968-08 (Box 563)
      - "1969 stories," index (Box 563)
      - 1969-01 (Box 563)
      - 1969-02 (Box 563)
      - 1969-03 (Box 563)
      - 1969-04 (Box 563)
      - 1969-05 (Box 563)
      - 1969-06 (Box 563)
      - 1969-10 (Box 563)
      - "Story index 1970" (Box 563)
      - 1970-01 (Box 563)
      - 1970-03 (Box 563)
      - 1970-04 (Box 563)
      - 1970-05 (Box 563)
      - 1970-06 (Box 563)
      - 1970-08 (Box 563)
      - "A Memory of Two Mondays," call sheet, 1970 (Box 563)
      - 1971-01 to 1971-05, index and captions (Box 563)
      - Captions index, handwritten, 1971-1972 (Box 563)
      - 1972-01 to 1972- 07, index and captions (Box 563)
      - 1972-02 (Box 563)
      - 1972-03 (Box 563)
      - 1973-01 to 1974-06, "Contact prints in notebook", 1973-1974 (Box 563)
      - Story index, 1973 (Box 563)
      - 1973-01 to 1973-14, story index (Box 563)
      - 1973-12 (Box 563)
      - 1974-01 to 1974-20, story index, captions and contact print lists (Box 564)
      - 1974-02 (Box 564)
      - 1974-03 (Box 564)
      - 1974-04 (Box 564)
      - "Extra contacts in Roxbury," story lists from 1954-1959, 1975 January (Box 564)
      - "Double contact sheets in Roxbury," stories from 1957, 1960-1964, 1975 January (Box 564)
      - "The Hungarian P.E.N.," card, undated (Box 564)
      - 1975-01 to 1975-16 (Box 564)
      - 1975-01 to 1975-10, story index (Box 564)
      - 1975-08 (Box 564)
      - 1975-09 (Box 564)
      - 1976-01 to 1976-17 (Box 564)
      - 1977-01 to 1977-11 (Box 564)
      - 1977-01 (Box 564)
      - 1977-02 (Box 564)
      - 1977-03 to 1977-06, captions list (Box 564)
      - 1977-03 (Box 564)
      - 1977-04 (Box 564)
      - 1977-07 (Box 564)
      - 1977-09 (Box 564)
      - 1977-10 to 1977-12 (Box 564)
      - 1977-15 (Box 564)
      - 1977-21 (Box 564)
      - 1978-01 (Box 564)
      - [1978-03?] (Box 564)
      - 1978-10 (Box 564)
      - 1978-12 (Box 564)
      - 1979-05 (also includes 1978-12), 1978-1979 (Box 564)
      - 1979-16 (Box 564)
      - 1980-01 (Box 564)
      - 1980-10 (Box 564)
      - 1981-02 (Box 564)
      - 1981-05 (Box 564)
      - 1982-01 to 1982-02 (Box 564)
      - 1982-03 (Box 564)
      - 1982-04 (Box 564)
      - 1982-06 (Box 564)
      - Magnum Distribution 82-137, color captions, 1982 (Box 564)
      - 1983-06 (Box 564)
      - 1983-09 (Box 564)
      - Magnum Distribution 83-34, 1983 (Box 564)
      - Magnum Distribution 83-106, 1983 (Box 564)
      - 1984-02 (Box 564)
      - 1984-07 (Box 564)
      - Magnum Distribution 84-243, 1984 (Box 564)
      - 1985-01 (Box 564)
      - 1985-06 to 1985-07 (Box 564)
      - 1985-14 (Box 564)
      - "List of photos to be used for BW transparencies to be used in Portfolio", 1985 March 17 (Box 564)
      - Magnum Distribution D85-089, 1985 (Box 564)
        Death of a Salesman, film version.
      - Magnum Distribution D85-270, 1985 (Box 564)
        "Death of Yul Brynner"
      - 1985-01 to 1985-07, story list (Box 564)
      - 1986-01 (Box 564)
      - 1986-02 (Box 564)
      - 1986-03 (Box 564)
      - 1986-08 (Box 564)
      - 1986-09 (Box 564)
      - 1986-13 (Box 564)
      - 1987-01 (Box 565)
      - 1987-06 (Box 565)
      - 1987-07 (Box 565)
      - 1987-26 (Box 565)
      - 1987-27 (Box 565)
      - 1987-28 (Box 565)
      - 1987-29 (Box 565)
      - Magnum Distribution D88-073, 1988 (Box 565)
        "Arthur Miller and Edward Albee," color captions
      - Magnum Distribution D88-109, 1988 (Box 565)
        "Seville's Annual Feria Festival," color captions
      - 1988-06 (Box 565)
      - Magnum Distribution D88-186, 1988 (Box 565)
        "Glasnost"
      - 1988-07 (Box 565)
      - 1988-14 (Box 565)
      - 1988-15 (Box 565)
      - 1988-16 (Box 565)
      - Magnum Distribution D88-323, 1988 (Box 565)
        "Rebecca Miller," color captions
      - 1989-02 (Box 565)
      - 1989-04 (Box 565)
      - 1989-10 (Box 565)
      - 1989-11 (Box 565)
      - "USSR; Moscow and Lithuania Archives, 1989," Color Captions, Distribution D89-123 (Box 565)
      - "Liz Magnum London," correspondence, 1989 March 30 (Box 565)
      - "The Two Sides of the Wall," color captions, Distribution D89-262, ca. 1989 (Box 565)
      - 1989-18 (Box 565)
      - "Spain Captions", circa 1989 (Box 565)
      - 1990-02 (Box 565)
      - 1990-03 (Box 565)
      - 1990-04 (Box 565)
      - Magnum Distribution D90-564, circa 1990 (Box 565)
        "Moscow's Forgotten Children"
      - Magnum Distribution D90-564, circa 1990 (Box 565)
        "Brides of Prison"
      - Magnum Distribution D90-599, circa 1990 (Box 565)
        "Nelson Mandela interviewed by Arthur Miller"
      - 1990-14 (Box 565)
      - 1991-01 (Box 565)
      - Magnum Distribution D94-631, circa 1994 (Box 565)
        "Bhutan," color captions
      - 1994-01 (Box 565)
      - 1994-10 (Box 565)
      - 1996-05 (Box 565)
      - 1996-06 (Box 565)
      - 1996-08 (Box 565)
      - 1996-11 (Box 565)
      - 1996-17 (Box 565)
      - Magnum Distribution D96-527, 1996 (Box 565)
        "Alexander Calder," color captions
      - Magnum Distribution D96-503, 1996 (Box 565)
        "Joseph Brodsky"
      - Papp, Joseph, The Dybbuk (or Between Two Worlds ), theatre program, photocopy, circa 1996 (Box 565)
      - "Danube Book, negative numbers with page numbers", circa 1996 (Box 565)
  - Notebooks, 1954-1960
    Notebooks that document Morath's travel and work assignments.
    - Barcelona, undated (Box 566)
    - "France, Yul Brynner, Prague", 1958 (Box 566)
    - "Gaza, Refugee trip, Yul Brynner, C.B.S.", 1960 (Box 566)
    - "Iran II", undated (Box 566)
    - "Mercedes Formica", 1954 (Box 566)
    - "Mexico", 1959 February-April 1959; 2 (Box 566)
    - "Middle East: Lebanon, Syria, Jordan, Iran", 1956 (Box 566)
    - "Portugal", 1956 (Box 566)
    - "Provence", 1956 (Box 566)
    - "Romania", 1958 (Box 566)
    - "Spain", 1953-1956; 2 (Box 566)
    - "Spain", 1953-1956; 2 (Box 567)
    - "Toledo," Spain, 1955 January (Box 567)
    - "Touraine," France, 1960 October (Box 567)
    - "Tunisia I 59-31", undated (Box 567)
    - "Venice", 1954 (Box 567)
    - "Wachau, Yugoslavia, Wien, Prague, Bratislava", undated (Box 567)
    - "Madrid, Luis Escobar, and Mercedes Formica", undated (Box 567)
  - General Files, 1958-2012
    This subseries consists of Morath's personal and professional papers, and chiefly documents her work as a photographer and author. The files include Magnum Photos statements and reports, biographical writings, correspondence, exhibition material, financial records, notes and notebooks, print inventories, printed material, research material, travel records, and ephemera.
    Organized under three headings: Binders of Files, Personal Files, and Papers from File Drawers.
    - Binders of Files, (15 boxes)
      The binders consist of captions, correspondence, texts, notes, printed material, and contact sheet photocopies related to Morath's projects, which the Inge Morath Foundation housed in binders.
      - "Inge Morath reference pictures", 2002-2004 (Box 568)
      - "Inge Morath Fotografien 1952-1992 Monograph", undated (Box 568)
      - "Morath Story List," memos and printed material (photocopies), 1956-1989 (Box 569)
      - Magum binder, empty, undated (Box 569)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 570)
      - "Danube," notes and text, 1995 (Box 571)
        Includes some German translations of selected text and picture captions
      - "Bucher-Martinez book," notes and text, 1974 (Box 572)
      - "Inge Morath Xerox Madrid catalogue: Fotografia," photocopies, 1989 (Box 573)
      - "Text-all versions, Martinez Morath monographie," notes and text, undated (Box 574)
      - "Inge Morath texts: Chaikin book, Ruth Simon book and Mini Portraits book," notes and text, 1972-1991 (Box 575)
      - "In the Country," Connecticut book, 1972-1975 (Box 576)
      - "Pasternak book," notes and text, 1974-1976 (Box 577)
      - "Exhibitions: A-M", 1969-1977 (Box 578)
      - "Exhibitions: N-Z", 1974-1977 (Box 579)
      - "List of 11 by 14 inches Fiber prints in Magnum New York office," (photocopies), 1993 (Box 580)
      - "Color slide photocopies," of contact sheets, 1981-1986 (Box 581)
        Includes some correspondence, captions, and images from stories: 1981-02, 1983-09, and 1986-13.
      - "Slovenia contact photocopies", circa 2004 (Box 582)
        Photocopies of story: 2001-04.
    - Personal Files
      Organized under eight headings: Personal Documents, Equipment and Expenses, Magnum Photos, Early Projects, Russia, China, Other Projects, and Other Material.
      - Personal Documents
        - Birth certificates, Austrian papers, 1946-1959 (Box 583)
        - Academic documents, 1940-1971 (Box 583)
        - Work papers, metro card, correspondence, 1948-1970 (Box 583)
        - Work papers (photocopies), undated (Box 583)
        - England, 1948-1951 (Box 583)
          Includes the certificate for Morath's brief marriage with journalist and magazine editor Lionel Birch
        - Paris, 1959-1962 (Box 583)
        - Identification papers, 1946-1952 (Box 583)
        - United States citizenship, registration, 1957-1991; 2 (Box 583)
        - Passports, Austrian and British, 1948-1960 (Box 583)
        - Professional identification, press cards, 1947-1992 (Box 583)
        - Travel papers, 1967 (Box 583)
        - Medical travel vaccinations, 1956-1959 (Box 583)
        - United States passports and papers, 1962-1996 (Box 583)
        - United States, marriage and health, circa 1962 (Box 583)
        - Financial, 1978 (Box 583)
        - Paris apartment, 1981-1982 (Box 583)
      - Equipment and Expenses
        - Cameras and professional equipment, 1950-1980; 4 (Box 584)
        - Camera equipment receipts, brochures and printed material, 1989, undated (Box 584)
        - Itemized camera and equipment lists, 1956-1978 (Box 584)
        - Photography bills and tax receipts, 1969-1971 (Box 584)
        - Business expenses, 1977-1978 (Box 584)
        - Photo lab advertisements, undated (Box 584)
        - East Street Gallery, 1972 (Box 584)
        - Photographic and darkroom, printed material, undated (Box 584)
        - Insurance, 1963-1967 (Box 584)
        - Guarantees and warranties, 1963-1969 (Box 584)
        - Repair invoices from Ernst Leitz GmbH, 1972 (Box 584)
        - List of cameras and photographic equipment, undated (Box 584)
      - Magnum Photos
        - Writings about Magnum, undated (Box 585)
        - Correspondence, 1949-1980; 2 (Box 585)
        - Henry Cartier-Bresson, notes, 1963, undated; 2 (Box 585)
        - Accounts, 1953-1957 (Box 585)
        - Legal documents, 1963-1972 (Box 585)
        - Licensing, 1958-1969 (Box 585)
        - Prints, exhibitions, 1962-1967 (Box 585)
        - Meetings, agreements, minutes, 1955-1994; 7 (Box 585)
        - Meetings, agreements, minutes, circa 1950 (Box 585)
        - Financial statements, 1959-1978; 22 (Box 586)
        - Financial statements, 1955-1970; 9 (Box 587)
      - Early Projects
        Consists of notes, correspondence, financial statements, contracts, projects, publicity, print lists, requests for photographs, exhibit material, and clippings.
        - Telegram, hotel list and air transport memorabilia, 1955, undated (Box 588)
        - Captions for Ernest Haas story, Salerno, Italy Orphanage, undated (Box 588)
        - "Worker priests," story captions, clippings, notes, 1953; 10 (Box 588)
        - Bernier telegram, 1955 (Box 588)
        - Spain: captions, print photocopies, 1954, undated (Box 588)
        - Venice: correspondence, notes, brochure, 1955 (Box 588)
        - South Africa correspondence, brochures, notes, 1955 (Box 588)
        - Portugal correspondence, notes, brochures, 1956 (Box 588)
        - Middle East, correspondence, notes, 1956; 4 (Box 589)
        - Middle East, travel tickets and papers, 1956 (Box 589)
        - Lebanon, 1956 (Box 589)
        - Jordan, 1956 (Box 589)
        - Iran, 1956 (Box 589)
        - Iraq, 1956 (Box 589)
        - Syria, 1956 (Box 589)
        - Valencia, Spain, 1957 (Box 590)
        - Monet, Jean, 1957 (Box 590)
        - Datebook, probably not kept by Morath, 1958 (Box 590)
        - Vienna, 1958 (Box 590)
        - Solomon and Sheba, 1958 (Box 590)
        - Trompe-l'œil Baroque/Prague story, 1958 (Box 590)
        - Tunisia, 1959; 3 (Box 590)
        - Refugee story, 1960 (Box 590)
        - Bankers Trust, 1961 (Box 590)
        - Saul Steinberg, 1965 (Box 590)
        - Danube, 1958 (Box 590)
        - Romania, 1958; 2 (Box 590)
        - "Trip to Reno", 1960 (Box 590)
        - Note from Montgomery Clift on set of The Misfits, 1960 (Box 590)
        - The Misfits, 1960 (Box 590)
        - The Misfits, screenplay by Arthur Miller, 1960 July 13 (Box 590)
      - Russia
        Documents Morath's travel to Russia including correspondence, writings, diaries, notebooks, printed material, and ephemera.
        - Correspondence, 1987-1994; 5 (Box 591)
        - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 591)
        - Russian Diary, 1965-1969; 5 (Box 591)
        - Moscow Diary, 1987-1989; 5 (Box 592)
        - "Avant-garde Russian artists", 1989 (Box 592)
        - Writings and notes, undated (Box 592)
        - 2 spiral notebooks, 1983 (Box 592)
        - "Russian collapse," notebook, 1989 (Box 592)
        - Russian language study notebook, undated (Box 593)
        - Tolstoy Foundation research for Russian book, 1970; 2 (Box 593)
        - Memorabilia, 1989, undated (Box 593)
        - Printed material, 1987 (Box 593)
      - China
        - Correspondence, 1974-1985; 7 (Box 593)
        - China diary, 1983; 2 (Box 594)
        - Spiral notebook, 1979 (Box 594)
        - Language study notebook, undated (Box 594)
        - Black-and-white prints, undated (Box 594)
        - Color negatives and prints, 2 rolls, 1977 (Box 594)
        - Maps, undated (Box 594)
        - Printed material, 1977, undated (Box 594)
        - Postcards and travel brochures, 1977-1979 (Box 594)
        - Research material, 1973-1981, undated; 7 (Box 595)
        - China diary, 1978-1980, undated; 3 (Box 596)
        - Captions, 1979, undated; 3 (Box 596)
        - "Salesman in Beijing", 1983 (Box 596)
        - Map of China, pencil and ink drawing, undated (Box 596)
        - Story lists on index cards, undated (Box 596)
        - Print lists: China shows, Museum of Modern Art, Vienna, 1980 (Box 596)
        - Accordion folder notebook, undated (Box 596)
        - Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 597)
        - Notebooks, 1978, undated; 3 (Box 597)
        - Language study material, undated; 2 (Box 597)
        - Foreign Theatre, printed material, undated (Box 597)
      - Other Projects
        - Colombia, 1982 (Box 598)
        - Egypt, 1981 (Box 598)
        - Israel, notebook, 1972 (Box 598)
        - Japan, 1984, undated; 4 (Box 598)
          Color prints from a Japanese stage production based on Gone with the Wind
        - Montevideo and Uruguay, 1998 (Box 598)
        - Nantucket research material, 1978-1979; 3 (Box 598)
        - Paris and Belgium trip, 1998 September (Box 599)
        - Venezuela, 1981 (Box 599)
        - Vienna, 1978; 2 (Box 599)
        - Vilnius, 1985 (Box 599)
        - Captions, East Anglia and Norwich, 1984, 1987 (Box 599)
        - Clippings and publicity, 1970-1989; 2 (Box 599)
      - Other Material
        - Biographical writings, 1954-2000; 9 (Box 600)
          Includes awards, résumés, biographical notes, and writings about Morath's work
        - Awards, 1984-2000; 2 (Box 601)
          Includes an honorary Doctor of Fine Arts award from the University of Hartford
        - Writings, 1969-1986; 5 (Box 601)
        - Writings, 1965-2001; 5 (Box 602)
        - Personalities, 1953-2007; 7 (Box 602)
          Includes material about Alexander Calder, Henri Cartier-Bresson, Robert Delpire, and Anna Fárová
        - Personalities, 1940-2001; 2 (Box 603)
          Includes: Ernst Haas and Saul Steinberg
        - Business correspondence, David Shewitz, Menninger story, Connecticut book, Stevenson book correspondence, Chinese Encounters, notes, 1961-1981; 4 (Box 603)
        - In Russia, reviews, photography, exhibits, shows; requests for photographs; Miami Conference; Reviews: Bucher-Martinez, Neikrug Galleries; requests for criticism, 1969-1979; 8 (Box 604)
        - Requests for photographs; lectures; correspondence; Lithuania; Colombia; Spain; S. Fischer Publishing House; Reich Verlag correspondence; exhibits; shows; Rhode Island School of Design; Pasternak book correspondence, 1962-1992; 12 (Box 605)
        - Jacques Kaplan show; Paris book; Photograph Austria correspondence; Aperture; Bucher negative numbers, 1977-1998; 6 (Box 606)
        - Russian artists and personalities; copies of biographical papers; book correspondence, 1971-1996; 6 (Box 607)
        - In the Country, Death of a Salesman, correspondence; Iran correspondence, 1977-2000; 7 (Box 608)
        - Invitations; miscellaneous notes; Magnum Photos bills and correspondence; Repertoire Salisbury project, 1979-1992; 6 (Box 609)
        - China reviews; inventory lists; Vienna book correspondence; Crucible shooting schedule; programs and exhibits; Batuz print orders, 1976-2002; 9 (Box 610)
          Includes Vienna book and exhibit correspondence.
        - "Orf-Landesstudio Hamburg, in Kultur Kompass, Interview M. Mayraker liber 1. Morath retrospective in Fotohof", 1982 (Box 610)
        - Print lists, 1958-1989, undated; 8 (Box 611)
        - Print lists (photocopies), undated (Box 612)
        - Personal and family papers, ephemera, 1935-1995; 4 (Box 612)
        - Personal and family papers, 1990-1993; 3 (Box 613)
          Consists of correspondence and papers about her Morath's mother, Matilda "Titti" Morath.
        - Manuscript in German, 1858 (Box 613)
    - Papers from File Drawers
      Material from file drawers maintained by Morath and her assistant.
      - Correspondence, 1963-1999; 4 (Box 614)
        Correspondents include Phillip Roth, Adlai Stevenson, and Saul Steinberg. Also includes letters about "The conservation of photographs," "The ICP portrait course," and Inge Morath's 75th birthday
      - Professional correspondence, 2001 (Box 614)
      - Magnum Photos, correspondence, 2001-2006; 3 (Box 614)
      - Copyright by Inge Morath, 1989-1998 (Box 614)
        Correspondence pertaining to a documentary film about Morath produced Kick Films
      - Inge Morath: Ein Filmportrait von Sabine Eckhard (photocopy), undated (Box 615)
      - Writings and lectures, 1996-2000 (Box 615)
      - Biographies, 1994-1999; 4 (Box 615)
        Biographies and information about Morath, including a résumé
      - "Spain," articles and reviews, 1994 (Box 615)
      - Donau Festival Niederosterreich 96 "Fotokunst," clippings and lectures, 1995-1996; 2 (Box 616)
      - Ab 40, 1994 February (Box 616)
      - Aperture 151, 1998 (Box 616)
      - Antagonismes. 30 ans de photographie autrichienne. Catalogue d'exposition - Collectif, clippings (photocopies), 1996 (Box 616)
      - Brigitte, 1996 October 30 (Box 616)
      - Articles and reviews about Inge Morath, 1990-1997; 5 (Box 617)
      - Last Journey, clippings, 2003 (Box 617)
      - "Articles about personalities," clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 617)
      - "Other photographers," clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 618)
      - Foto Mundo, 1996 September (Box 618)
      - Spain: Inge Morath, press kit in Spanish, 1995 (Box 618)
      - Photography in New York International, 1996 (Box 618)
      - Galleries and collectors, correspondence, 1993 (Box 618)
      - "Forum Stadt...Paris Osterreich School," correspondence, 1992 (Box 618)
      - Organizers and curators of shows and projects, 1998-2001 (Box 618)
      - Galleries, consignment records, 2002-2003 (Box 618)